[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
usage of frequently used basic tosca
automation action modes such as
input
verify
dynamic buffer
constraint etc the explanation will be
done through hands-on demonstration
here we will understand the basic
automation steps such as handling of
text box drop downs radio options click
operations etc
first we need to scan the web page to
create the module
[Music]
we will select the desire application
window during the application selection
and proceed
[Music]
we will add all the controls including
drop downs text fields radio option
button etc from the web page using
select on screen option from the scan
wizard
[Music]
we will now check and verify that the
controls are identified uniquely through
the default properties
after that we need to save to create the
module and close the scan window
the module is created successfully with
the required controls
[Music]
next we will understand the approaches
to perform basic automation activities
[Music]
first we will navigate to test case
section and create a new sample test
case in
then we will drag and drop the newly
created module into this test case
for data entry we need to provide the
test data in test step value column and
select the input action mode
the options for any drop down columns
are available in step attributes value
which are loaded during scanning
we can select the required option from
here
by default this action mode is auto
populated as input for any input or
clickable controls
for any text field we need to enter the
data in the value attribute
similarly we will provide the input data
for rest of the input fields
[Music]
to perform click operation in button
next we will provide the keyword click
with curly brackets or we will use
capital x in value with input action
mode
the first option will perform the mouse
movements
[Music]
now the test step is completed
now we will execute the step in
scratchbook to perform the data
population in the application and click
on next button through automation
it will take few seconds to complete the
execution of this step
[Music]
that's all about the data entry and
click operation
now we will understand the action mode
verify by performing verification of
first name field
also we will create a dynamic buffer to
store version number from verification
step which is available in header
section of the application
in order to create automated
verification step
we need to create the module for enter
insurance data web page
[Music]
during the scanning we will add two
controls
first one is the link control from the
top section which contains the version
number
we will rename it to branding instead of
big texts and
verify the uniqueness of the controls
and the properties
then we will select to add the first
name label control
now save the scan wizard to create
module and close it
[Music]
we will now drag and drop this new
module into the sample test case as test
step
we will rename the test step as it
performs the verification operation
[Music]
now we will perform the existence
verification of the step attribute first
name
select the action mode as verify
there is multiple verification
properties are available in value
here we will select the exists property
with binary true value
the step will be marked past if
condition satisfied
similarly we will add the verification
step for the branding attribute
here we will verify the exact text of
the link against the inner text property
to create dynamic buffer to store
version we will replace the version
numbers with the keyword curly bracket
xp then buffer name buffer version if in
third brackets and end the curly bracket
during execution it will create and
store the extracted version number into
this dynamic buffer
[Music]
we will execute this verification step
in the scratchbook
it will take few seconds to be completed
[Music]
after the execution the scratchbook
execution logs will be appeared
it will contains the verification step
details
as though the expected and actual values
are matched both the verification steps
are passed
if we navigate to the buffer viewer
section we can see the new buffer with
name buffer version has been created
with the version number
the action mode constraint is used for
checking of a particular value which is
mostly used in the tables column
in this particular tutorial we will find
row of text worldwide cover from the
first column and then capture the
corresponding value from the column gold
same thing can be done using a loop
which is a more complex approach
first we need to scan the web page to
create the module
we will select the correct application
window during the application selection
and click on scan button to proceed
[Music]
from this xkin window we will select the
corresponding price table control and
check the uniqueness
also we will add the next button which
may require in future
click on save to create the module and
close the x scan window
now we will navigate to test case
section and create a sample test case
and rename it
[Music]
then we will drag and drop the newly
created module into this test case
here the first step would be we need to
search the text worldwide cover from
first column using the action mode
constraint
from the price table attribute we will
select the cell label as one dollar
enter cell value as worldwide cover
[Music]
and change the action mode as constraint
for the cell attribute which is
available within row attribute
we will keep the row label as is
now we need to capture the value of
column gold
so we will select the next cell as the
gold which represents the column name
change the action mode as buffer which
will be used to store the column value
and enter the buffer name as buffer gold
in value
test step is now completed
we will execute this test step in the
scratchbook
it will take few seconds to be completed
[Music]
after the execution the scratchbook
execution logs will be appeared
from the execution logs we can see that
the buffer buffer gold is created with
the extracted cell value
that's all about constraint
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about basic usage of action
mode input verify and constraint
we will learn more about tosca features
in next video
[Music]
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query